Marie-Claire Beaulieu Collection of Greek Epitaphs MS190
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Marie-Claire Beaulieu Collection of Greek Epitaphs
2007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
MS190
16 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized in one series.
Biographical / Historical
Marie-Claire Beaulieu has been Assistant Professor, Department of Classics, Tufts University since 2010 with a secondary appointment in the Department of Religion. Before that she was Assistant Professor, Department of Classics, at the University of Manitoba, Winnipeg (2009-2010) and lecturer at the Department of Classics, Dartmouth College, NH from 2008-2009. Her research areas are Greek Religion, Epigraphy, Medieval Latin, and Digital Humanities. She received a Ph. D. from the Department of Classics, University of Texas, Austin in 2008 and her BA and MA from the Universit&#233 de Montr&#233al, Centre d'&#201tudes Classiques in 2001 and 2003 respectively.
Scope and Contents
The digital files in this collection were created by Marie-Claire Beaulieu of the Classics Department as part of her research and teaching activities. The collection includes images and transcriptions of Greek epitaphs.
Faculty research; Greek epitaphs; Greece -- History
- Marie-Claire Beaulieu collection of Greek epitaphs, 2007; MS190.001; 16 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs and TEI versions of epitaphs in both Ancient Greek and English.
  Arrangement
  This series is grouped by epitaph source.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Sarcophagus of Nedymos, Church of St-Lukas, Thiva, Greece, 2007; MS190.001.001
    Images and TEI translations relating to Epitaph of Nedymos, IG VII 2543-2545, c. 200-300.
    - Sarcophagus of Nedymos, Church of St-Lukas, Thiva, Greece, 2007; MS190.001.00001; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      General view of the sarcophagus of Nedymos. Shows the location of the sarcophagus in the church
      Thebes (Greece); Sarcophagi, Greek
    - Epitaph of Nedymos, part a. (hexameters), 2007; MS190.001.00002; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Text panel on the right-hand-side of the sarcophagus. The stone is slightly damaged and partly integrated into the church wall
      Thebes (Greece); Inscriptions
    - Rosette, 2007; MS190.001.00003; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Decorative panel on the right-hand side of the sarcophagus, near the mouth of the sarcophagus
      Thebes (Greece); Rosette (motif)
    - Foundations of the Church of St-Lukas, Thiva, Greece, 2007; MS190.001.00004; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Shows the successive reconstructions of the church
      Thebes (Greece); Church buildings--Reconstruction
    - IG VII 2543-2545 Thebes, IIIrd-IVth century AD. Three epigrams on a sarcophagus, 2007; MS190.001.00005
      English translation of three epigrams on a sarcophagus, c. 200-300.
      Thebes (Greece); Epitaphs
    - IG VII 2543-2545 Thebes, IIIrd-IVth century AD. Three epigrams on a sarcophagus, 2007; MS190.001.00006
      Greek text of three epigrams on a sarcophagus, c. 200-300.
    - IG VII 2543-2545: Epitaph of Nedymos (Thebes), 2007; MS190.001.00007; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire; Bishara, Kaitlyn; Freymuller, Brigid
      English translation of Epitaph of Nedymos (Thebes), c. 200-300.
    - IG VII 2543-2545: Epitaph of Nedymos (Thebes), 2007; MS190.001.00008; Bishara, Kaitlyn; Freymuller, Brigid
      Greek text of Epitaph of Nedymos (Thebes), c. 200-300.
  - Sarcophagus of Demetria, Aliki, Thasos, Greece, 2007; MS190.001.002
    Images and TEI translations relating to Epitaph of Demetria, IG XII 8,600, c. 100
    - Sarcophagus of Demetria, Aliki, Thasos, Greece, 2007; MS190.001.00009; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Shows the relative proportions of the sarcophagus and the fact that the ground has significantly risen. The periphery of the sarcophagus has been dug out in the course of the excavations led by the French School, and revealed that the sarcophagus was plundered
      Thasos (Greece); Sarcophagi, Greek
    - Epitaph of Demetria, 2007; MS190.001.00010; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Front panel of the sarcophagus with epitaph (black-and-white)
      Thasos (Greece); Inscriptions
    - Epitaph of Demetria, 2007; MS190.001.00011; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire
      Front panel of the sarcophagus with epitaph (color photograph)
    - IG XII.8,600: epitaph of Demetria (Thasos), 2007; MS190.001.00012; Beaulieu, Marie-Claire; Bishara, Kaitlyn; Freymuller, Brigid
      English translation of epitaph of Demetria (Thasos), c. 100.
      Thasos (Greece); Epitaphs
    - IG XII.8,600: epitaph of Demetria (Thasos), 2007; MS190.001.00013; Bishara, Kaitlyn; Freymuller, Brigid
      Greek text of epitaph of Demetria (Thasos), c. 100
  - Inscription IG VII 115-117, Megara, three epigrams, 2007; MS190.001.003
    TEI versions of three epigrams on a sarcophagus, IG VII 115-117, c. 400-500.
    - IG VII 115-117 Megara, IVth-Vth century AD. Three epigrams on a sarcophagus, 2007; MS190.001.00014
      English translation of three epigrams on a sarcophagus, c. 300-400.
      Megara (Greece); Epigrams
    - IG VII 115-117 Megara, IVth-Vth century AD. Three epigrams on a sarcophagus, 2007; MS190.001.00015
    - IG VII 115-117 Megara, IVth-Vth century AD. Three epigrams on a sarcophagus, 2007; MS190.001.00016
      Greek text of three epigrams on a sarcophagus, c. 300-400.